http://www.spca.org/privacy

AdoptFindapet - Adoptable PetsMobile AdoptionsAdoption Love StoriesHow to AdoptFAQLivestock AdoptionLivestock Adoption ApplicationOffsite Cat AdoptionsHelp AnimalsFosterFight Animal CrueltyReport Animal CrueltyHumane Education for KidsClinic ServicesOnline PharmacyAnimal SurrenderAnimal Control AgenciesWays To GiveVolunteerVolunteer LoginIndividual VolunteeringYouth VolunteeringGroup VolunteeringCourt Ordered Community ServiceFoster HeroesWays to GiveDonate OnlineMatching GiftsGiving CirclesMonthly GivingMemorial GivingHonor GivingCorporate PartnershipShop To GiveBuy a BrickCar DonationGive a Dog a BedSponsor a Habitat - DallasSponsor a Habitat - McKinneyWish ListDonate MonthlyEventsEvent CalendarPaws CauseStrut Your MuttFur BallDonateConnect with UsPet OwnersSpay & NeuterClinic ServicesOnline PharmacyPet Care TipsPeople ProgramsPet Grief CounselingPet TrainingPet Training TipsMeet UsMissionHelping Animals of TexasHistoryBoard of DirectorsLeadershipFAQNewsConnect with UsDonate
Login/RegisterContactLocations & HoursFAQ
Event CalendarNewsHow to AdoptAnimal SurrenderReport Abuse/CrueltySpay/Neuter AppointmentsCareer Center
Search:
Search
Privacy Policy
The SPCA of Texas has created this Privacy Policy to explain why we collect particular information and how we will protect your personal privacy within our website. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the website located at www.spca.org.
In order to fully understand your rights we encourage you to read this Privacy Policy. By visiting our website, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy"). SPCA of Texas reserves the right at any time and without notice to change this Privacy Policy simply by posting such changes on our Site. Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting.
Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, this Privacy Policy notifies you of:
What personally identifiable information of yours is collected through the Site;
Who collects such information;
How such information is used;
With whom your information may be shared;
What choices you have regarding collection, use and distribution of your information;
What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control; and
How you can correct any inaccuracies in your information.
Questions regarding this statement should be directed to SPCA of Texas by sending an e-mail. Please reference this Privacy Policy in your subject line.
What Information We Collect
Our registration forms require users to give us contact information that may include name, e-mail address, format preference (HTML vs. Text), address, interests, and similar information. We do not request or store sensitive information from our visitors, such as credit card or social security numbers. The SPCA of Texas does not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you voluntarily submit such information to us. This information is used solely by the SPCA of Texas for internal purposes.
Use of Information:
The SPCA of Texas respects your privacy and has instituted policies intended to ensure that your personal information is handled in a safe and responsible manner. We may use this information to deliver to you information we think you may be interested in, as well as for trend analysis, pattern detection, and site administration. It is important to note that the SPCA of Texas does not sell, trade or share its lists.
Non-personal demographic and profile data is used to tailor your experience at our site, showing you content we think you might be interested in. Occasionally, the SPCA of Texas may contact registered visitors who have provided their personally identifiable information through the website in order to conduct surveys seeking feedback about their experience on this site. These surveys are used for quality assurance purposes to improve our level of customer service.
The SPCA of Texas uses personally identifiable information you provide about yourself: a) to respond to your questions or comments about SPCA of Texas services; b) to fulfill requests to volunteer; c) to process your donation, verify your credit card and send you a tax-deductible receipt; d) confirm a donation; e) to thank you; f) to send you additional information about SPCA of Texas programs, services and needs that we believe will interest you; g) to protect against a threat of safety or destruction of property; and h) to protect against legal liability.
We will only disclose personally identifiable information to third parties when (i) the person submitting the information authorizes us to do so; (ii) sharing the information is a necessary operation of the site (i.e. to process credit card information); and (iii) we are required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on the SPCA of Texas or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of the SPCA of Texas, the site or the visitors to the site, and/or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of visitors to the site or the public.
The SPCA of Texas uses non-identifying basic information (aggregate data), on occasion, to share with sponsors, partners, other third-party vendors, or for internal marketing purposes to encourage fundraising.
The SPCA of Texas may disclose to third parties aggregate statistics (e.g., total number of donors, total amount of donations for specific periods, average gift size, and total number of volunteers for specific projects or events). These statistics will not include any personally identifying information.
The SPCA of Texas will not use personal information in any way other than described in this policy.
By visiting this Web site you agree that no information you submit to the site shall contain libelous or otherwise unlawful, abusive or obscene material. You are solely responsible for the content of any information you provide to the SPCA of Texas.
Our Donor Confidentiality Pledge
The SPCA of Texas values your support and is committed to protecting your privacy. We maintain strict donor information privacy policies and take great care to ensure that unauthorized persons do not compromise your information.
Personal information remains confidential, and the SPCA of Texas will not sell, share or trade our donors’ names or personal information with any other entity, nor send mailings to our donors on behalf of other organizations.
This policy applies to all information received by the SPCA of Texas both online and offline, on any Platform (“Platform,” includes the SPCA of Texas' website and mobile applications), as well as any electronic, written, or oral communications. To the extent any donations are processed through a third-party service provider, our donors’ information will only be used for purposes necessary to transact, fulfill and or account for donations that you have authorized.
Internet Protocol Address
We collect an IP address from all visitors to our Site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track users' movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site, and deliver customized, personalized content. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
Use of "Cookies"
Our site may use cookies to enhance your experience while using our site. Cookies are pieces of information that some websites transfer to the computer that is browsing that website and are used for record-keeping purposes at many websites. Use of cookies makes web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular website and to make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard.
Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our Site will not function properly when you view them.
Secure Environment
The SPCA of Texas' transaction handling policies allow you to make safe donations, whether in person, by phone, by mail, or online. Cash, check, or credit card transactions are handled so as to ensure complete donor information confidentiality. Third parties handle the SPCA of Texas' online credit card verification process. These organizations require your name, address, credit card number, and expiration date to process your transaction. Their state-of- the-art firewalls and encryption technology offer the highest level of security to ensure the confidentiality of your transaction. The SPCA of Texas and our third party vendors will not use your information for any purpose outside of these necessary processes.
All information provided to SPCA of Texas is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. We also protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our site that is only accessible by certain qualified employees of the SPCA of Texas.
Tell-A-Friend
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and e-mail address. The SPCA of Texas will automatically send the friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the site. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail.
Other Web Sites
Our site contains links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which SPCA of Texas has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours.
Opt-Out
You may opt-out of receiving communications from our partners and/or from us by sending an email to our webmaster with your complete name, address and email address.
Disclaimer
This site and all of the materials on or referenced by the site are provided on an "as is" basis. In no event shall the SPCA of Texas be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, punitive, or consequential damages of any kind whatsoever with respect to the use of this site. You agree that you are using this site solely at your own risk.
Indemnification
By using the SPCA of Texas website and all its contents, you agree to defend, indemnify and hold the SPCA of Texas harmless from any and all claims, damages, costs and expenses, including attorneys' fees, arising from or related to your use of the site. Your use of this site constitutes an agreement between you and the SPCA of Texas. This agreement, which consists of the terms and conditions set forth herein, shall be governed by, construed under and enforced in accordance with the laws of the State of Texas, without regard to any conflict of law provisions. User acknowledges and consents to jurisdiction in Texas. Any action in connection with, relating to and/or arising from this Agreement shall be brought exclusively in Dallas, Texas, in a federal or state court of competent jurisdiction. This agreement is effective unless and until terminated by either you or the SPCA of Texas. You may terminate this agreement at any time by notifying the SPCA of Texas by email or mail. The SPCA of Texas may also terminate this agreement at any time and may do so immediately without notice, and accordingly deny you access to the site, if in the SPCA of Texas' sole discretion you fail to comply with any term or provision of this agreement. Possible evidence of use of this site for illegal purposes may be provided to law enforcement authorities in the discretion of the SPCA of Texas. This is the entire agreement between the parties related to the use of this site.
Contacting the Web Site
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, you can contact:
SPCA of Texas - Society For The Prevention of Cruelty to Animals
http://spca.org/
You can also send an e-mail.
Learn More
Foster
Love Puppies & Kittens?
Cuddle puppies and kittens, dote on dogs and cats, provide post-operative care for canines and felines and teach four-legged foster friends what snuggling is all about.
Learn More
AdoptFindapet - Adoptable PetsMobile AdoptionsAdoption Love StoriesHow to AdoptFAQLivestock AdoptionLivestock Adoption ApplicationOffsite Cat AdoptionsHelp AnimalsFosterFight Animal CrueltyReport Animal CrueltyHumane Education for KidsClinic ServicesOnline PharmacyAnimal SurrenderAnimal Control AgenciesWays To GiveVolunteerVolunteer LoginIndividual VolunteeringYouth VolunteeringGroup VolunteeringCourt Ordered Community ServiceFoster HeroesWays to GiveDonate OnlineMatching GiftsGiving CirclesMonthly GivingMemorial GivingHonor GivingCorporate PartnershipShop To GiveBuy a BrickCar DonationGive a Dog a BedSponsor a Habitat - DallasSponsor a Habitat - McKinneyWish ListDonate MonthlyEventsEvent CalendarPaws CauseStrut Your MuttFur BallDonateConnect with UsPet OwnersSpay & NeuterClinic ServicesOnline PharmacyPet Care TipsPeople ProgramsPet Grief CounselingPet TrainingPet Training TipsMeet UsMissionHelping Animals of TexasHistoryBoard of DirectorsLeadershipFAQNewsConnect with UsDonate
AdoptVolunteerReport AbuseClinicsLocations
Behavior and Training Tips
Learn Tips and Tricks!
Learn Now!
SPCA of Texas Voices
"I'm absolutely in LOVE with Kitty (formerly Kaleigh). I know her name isn't original at all but I just started calling her that until I could think of a name and it just stuck - it's so her! I've attached two photos - she's seriously the most beautiful kitty in the world! She loves to steal tennis balls and bones from her dog sister - she thinks she's a dog! She enjoys going for walks and car rides, snuggling with mom, bird watching, drinking from the sink, playing with her pipe cleaners and getting into mom's makeup in the mornings. I couldn't 'imagine life without her. She's the absolute best!"
Laureen Jankins
Pet Owner
